Brother?
Ed!
Humans die all too quickly.
Brother! Brother!
It can't be! There's no way
Brother can be dead!
Dead?
That's right, dead.
They'll all be dead.
Only the homunculi will survive.
Brother can't die!
That's not right! Brother... Brother!
This is real life.
Perhaps he just
hadn't paid enough.
We always come
just a little short of the price.
Hey, are you all right?!
Colonel Archer!
I need to use that car.
Colonel, where are you going?
The Führer's residence.
Rebels have broken in.
That was a misunderstanding. It was just Lt. Hawkeye there.
Hawkeye?
What is she doing here?!
Please stop!
The Führer ordered us to question her
at the command center!
What are you guys plotting?!
Colonel! Colonel!
Please calm down, Colonel!
At this level, all you'll do
is spend my lives.
I was a little curious what would happen
if my whole body were to explode.
Is that how badly you want to become Führer?
I can see right through your petty ambitions.
But you should have
spent more time on this.
After attempting assassination, you won't ever be able to sit in a seat of power again.
I just can't forgive myself for acting like such a fool.
This is the only way I can
make amends to dead friends.
Then go apologize to them alone.
Give Brig. Gen. Hughes my regards.
Father!
Not to worry. I caught the rebel.
I'm sorry I didn't follow your orders, Father,
but I wanted to pay you back for looking after me.
This is one of the humans
whom you said were foolish.
Father? What is the matter, Father?
What have you done?!
U-Um... I took this out of the safe.
I didn't want your precious things
to be lost if there was a fire, Father.
Father...
This is why I call you fools!
King Bradley...
How many times
do I have to kill you...
before you die?
Stop!
What? What has he done?
Gluttony?
Alchemic decomposition?
How could you?!
I told you, you can't use alchemy!
That much more has been lost!
Stay back!
Do not touch me!
What do you think you're doing?
Brother is not dead yet.
See? He's still so warm.
His soul is still inside the gate.
All I have to do is
bring it back from there.
The way he did so for me.
Don't! If you do that...
I...
was turned into a Philosopher's Stone because of the sacrifices of many.
No, I might have died
back on that day to begin with.
Al...
Which is why...
Watch out.
Brother...
Colonel! Colonel!
Colonel!
Roy Mustang!
Al?
Wh-What is this?!
Where are we?!
At the gate.
Where does it go through to?
As I remember, it went to a city called London when I passed through it.
That's what Pop called it.
Pop?! You mean Hohenheim of Light?!
Yeah.
Then he's still alive!
You'd better not.
There's no telling what will happen.
I'm going to go see Hohenheim!
I'm going to kill him!
Take me to where Hohenheim is!
Don't interfere!
I'm going there!
The place where Hohenheim is!
The place where he is!
The place where Dad is!
Al...
Ed... you're alive?
Yeah...
Why am I crying?
Huh?
Al transmuted you—your dead body.
He used the Philosopher's Stone to restore my body and soul?
Then what happened to him?!
Are you telling me that he's gone?
Al! Al! Al!
Al!
How could this happen?
How could I lose the Philosopher's Stone,
in the state I'm in?
I'll have to get Pride to drive some more foolish humans into a corner.
Gluttony? What are you doing here?
You must be hungry.
Wait! You recognize me, don't you?!
Hurry and get going.
I hate to ask,
but can you take him too?
What about you, Ed?
I'm going to destroy this place
to make sure nobody ever seeks the Philosopher's Stone again.
Right. You can come along
afterward by yourself, right?
After all, you've now got some fine legs there.
If what Pop said is true,
then right now, Al's body and soul
are inside the gate.
There can be no other
price for a life.
Even if I offer all of myself, it might not do any good.
But still,
there's no reason for you to
have to go away. Come back, Al.
How is everyone?
Things are finally starting to calm down here in Central.
Owing to the Führer's disappearance,
the new government assumed power surprisingly quickly,
and the military handed over their political decision-making authority to the Assembly.
But it looks like the wars are going to continue
against those countries who are attacking us all over.
Even so, the policies toward Ishbal
have been reversed,
and I'd like to believe that everything else
is getting better, little by little.
I think that Brigadier General Mustang's return will still be a while off.
Would you stop
looking down like that?
The plan was perfect, but I didn't arrive in time, and as a result...
There's no such thing as perfect.
This whole world is imperfect.
That's why it's so beautiful.
How has Alphonse-kun been doing since then?
I know that when he was found, he was still a ten-year-old boy,
but I was surprised that he had lost all of his memories
since the day they tried to transmute their mother.
Does he still not remember anything that happened?
And will Edward-san really never again...
Sensei!
So Ed is really nowhere to be found, after all?
Even if someone does
give up their life as the price,
they probably still cannot
attain a human transmutation.
Maybe the reason why
Al is in that form
is because the four years of time
they spent together
was the price he had to pay.
Al has been reading books on alchemy recently,
the way he did long ago.
It's almost like he's doing it
to keep from forgetting about Ed.
And as for that boy Wrath,
Winry put some Automail on him.
The ones she had prepared for Ed.
Where is he now?
He left.
Is that so?
You want to study again?
Mm-hmm, at your place, Sensei.
Is that okay?
I want to study more
about alchemy and equivalent exchange.
And one day,
I want to see Brother again.
I don't know what I should do.
But if I learn more alchemy, then someday,
I'll see Brother again.
That's the feeling I get.
Al...
Is that all right?
I just can't help myself
against those eyes.
Al,
promise me one thing.
I'm going to keep training
more and more
to become the greatest
Automail mechanic around.
So promise me that
you'll come home.
That you'll come home
in one piece.
I'll be okay. I'll study, and I'm sure I'll find Brother and come home.
That's enough for today.
Thank you for coming along with us, Dr. Hohenheim.
Are you all really practicing magic?
In mythology, there is
an island named Thule.
Those of us in the Thule Society
believe it to be the land where God dwells,
and we are searching for
a path that will lead us to it.
With your continued help,
we will work towards that end.
I am looking for a path myself,
Professor Haushofer.
Fourteen marks for just one?
That's positively awful.
How long is this inflation
going to continue?
What's going on, Edward?
That.
Liquid-fuel rockets? Goddard?
He's an American,
but I hear there's another guy in Transylvania doing the same research.
His name's not Dracula, right?
His name is Oberth,
and apparently, he's still a student.
I'm going to go meet him.
What will you do
once you meet him?
He's thinking of using rockets to go out into space.
Maybe I can get closer to my world
by going out into space.
There's ether out there, and all.
Haven't you read Einstein?
That guy is pretty iffy.
If you can't use alchemy, you'll use mechanical technology, huh?
I should have been able to bind his soul and body together and recreate him.
But the next thing I knew,
I had come to this world by myself.
Passing through to here
was the only way
for you to keep from
losing your mind and body.
You must have done so unconsciously.
But I've once again lost that which
Al did so much to give me.
We can't say that
everything is perfect.
The whole world is
imperfect, after all.
I had meant to give my own life as the price for transmuting Al.
And yet, I'm still alive.
Maybe I did obtain something
without paying the price after all.
Or maybe Al is still there.
You two have been
journeying together.
The people you met
during that time,
the things you saw,
your pain, your effort,
everything that you experienced...
That could be the price you paid, couldn't it?
I don't know right now what
I should do to get back to you.
But you can bet that
I'm coming back.
We'll meet again, Al!
Man must pay an equal price in order to obtain anything.
That is the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
But the real world is imperfect,
and there was no law that could explain everything.
Same with the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
Even so, we believe...
that man cannot obtain anything
without paying a price.
The pain that we received
must have been the price
we paid to obtain something.
And by paying the price of effort,
everyone will certainly be able to obtain something.
Equivalent exchange is not the law of the world.
That's the promise Brother
and I made with each other
until the day we meet again.